On 23 April 2005, YouTube posted its first video.
2005年4月23日，YouTube 发布了它的第一个视频。
20 years later, YouTube is the world’s number one streaming service, where users clock billions of hours of watching every day.
20年后，YouTube 成为全球第一的流媒体服务平台，用户每天在上面观看的时长累计达数十亿小时。
That’s the vision of YouTube the company promotes — professional, entertaining and loud — but from one perspective, it’s all a facade.
这是该公司对外推广的 YouTube 形象——专业、有趣又热闹——但从某个角度看，这全是表象。
Through another lens, the essence of YouTube is more like this video from 2020.
换个角度看，YouTube 的本质更像是2020年的这段视频。
Before I watched, it had only been seen twice.
在我观看之前，它只被看过两次。
A man points the camera out of his bedroom window as the winter snow falls.
一个男人把镜头对着卧室窗外，外面正下着冬雪。
“Here it is,” he says.
“就是这个，”他说。
“The falling snow.”
“飘落的雪。”
A bird lands on a nearby fence.
一只鸟落在附近的篱笆上。
19 minutes go by.
19分钟过去了。
Nothing happens.
什么也没发生。
When we just focus on what’s popular, we miss how the vast majority of people actually use YouTube as uploaders, and overlook the role it plays in our society, says Ryan McGrady, a senior researcher.
资深研究员瑞安·麦格雷迪说，当我们只关注热门内容时，就会看不到绝大多数人作为上传者实际上是如何使用 YouTube 的，也会忽视它在我们社会中所起的作用。
This is not just the case with YouTube but with every major online video platform around the world.
不只是 YouTube，世界上每一个主要的在线视频平台都是如此。
For example, if you spend some time dipping into the corners of Douyin and Kuaishou, two of China’s most popular online video apps, you could see a side of the Internet that sometimes feels lost, one full of pure, unvarnished self-expression.
比如，抖音和快手同属中国最受欢迎的在线视频应用之列，如果你花些时间到这两个平台的角落里随意翻看，就能看到互联网有时让人觉得已经消失的一面——这一面充满了纯粹、质朴的自我表达。
It’s an entire world that the algorithm won’t show you.
那是算法不会展示给你的一整个世界。
Most of these videos are poorly produced, lack context or just meaninglessly show this and that.
这些视频大多制作粗糙，缺乏背景交代，或者只是毫无意义地拍拍这个、拍拍那个。
They exist because people need a digital attic to store their memories.
它们之所以存在，是因为人们需要一个数字阁楼来存放自己的记忆。
It’s an Internet unshaped by the pressures of algorithms — a glimpse into a place where content doesn’t have to perform, where it can simply exist.
这是一个不受算法压力塑造的互联网——让人得以一窥这样一个地方：在那里，内容不必刻意表现，可以只是单纯地存在。
And perhaps the most important thing about these videos is that if you watch enough of them, you can piece together a complete narrative of life, work, and society in a specific region and time period.
而这些视频最重要的一点或许是：只要你看得足够多，就能拼凑出某个特定地区、特定时期的生活、工作和社会的完整叙事。
This knowledge could be — and sometimes is — more valuable than a book or an online class.
这种知识可能——有时确实——比一本书或一门网课更有价值。
“The Internet is deeply troubled, and we can’t ignore the way tech companies are exacerbating those problems,” McGrady says.
“互联网问题重重，我们不能无视科技公司是如何让这些问题不断恶化的，”麦格雷迪说。
“What makes me hopeful is that when you find a way to look at how people are really using the web, a lot of it still feels like the early Internet.
“让我感到有希望的是，当你找到方法去观察人们真正是如何使用网络的时候，会发现其中很多内容仍然像早期的互联网。
It’s expression, communication, and connection.
那是表达、交流和联结。
Fundamentally, it’s a place where regular people share themselves and do wonderful things.”
从根本上说，这是一个普通人分享自我、做美好事情的地方。”